Sue Darby

I look at and analyze your data to help determine where processes could be improved.

sue.a.darby@gmail.com

Summary

Sue Darby is a WordPress Manager & Site Developer who works with a variety of small businesses specializing in a variety of industries to setup and maintain your WordPress site.

Sue knows that your website is an important gateway to showcasing your goods or services. She understands that your site is one of your most powerful branding and marketing tools.

Sue has installed WordPress, managed and ensured updates and security for multiple sites and currently has openings for more sites. Additionally she has developed multiple static sites as well in 20+ years of being online.

Sue is a trained & certified MS Office Master and is well versed in many software packages and programming languages.

Sue holds a Bachelors in Bachelors Business Management & Information Technology, Bachelors Business Management Practice & Office Applications from Charter College

Experience

Senior Services Technician at State of Alaska, Division of Senior & Disabilities, Provider Certification & Compliance

February 2014 - Present (3 years 1 month)

I pull data reports and track where applications are and how the process can be further streamlined or adjusted for efficiencies

- * Compile business policies and procedures into searchable staff manual including diagrams to improve clarity
- * Explain new technical tools in software and the benefits to a process to increase efficiency by 50-75%
- *Use of the unit's SharePoint intranet to create tracking tools for better time management
- *SharePoint tools became the template for reports generated in new division-wide database
- *Team leadership for up to 7 Division of Vocational Rehabilitation and Mature Alaskans Seeking Skills Training participants, teaching all aspects of clerical duties including application processing to archiving
- *Division & Unit Administrator and subject matter expert for SharePoint sites and tools
- *200 cubic feet of files sent to archiving (over 5000 files) including data input and correctly categorizing according to record retention schedule

- *Research purchase of date and bates stamping machine along with facilitating necessary maintenance
- *Coordinate efforts for mass mailings and record requests including letters, envelopes, and additional staff to complete the tasks on a strict schedule and maintaining confidentiality and HIPAA
- *Program in VB.net, edit and maintain complex checklist system for daily use
- *Create and maintain UMLs of internal processes
- *Provide detailed technical assistance to certified and non-certified providers and members of the public
- *Resourceful, self-sufficient problem solver often solving problems that are only partially in circle of responsibilities
- *Update and maintain secure PDF files for Certification Application (46 forms total)
- *Problem solves on the "go" often coming up with unconventional ideas for final or temporary solutions

Webmistress at iA3

October 2015 - Present (1 year 5 months)

iA3 is a service that gives you access to information and analytics about any automated systems you may have; anywhere, anytime. I am currently involved with the website, social media, Wikipedia and marketing efforts.

Business Consultant at Alaska Office Specialists

October 2008 - Present (8 years 5 months)

Alaska Office Specialists is a service-based business offering the services of technical writing, business writing, grant writing, document template creation, report writing with graphs and charts. Hosting, setup and maintenance of WordPress based sites, social media management.

visit www.alaskaos.com for more information.

Virtual Assistant Services such as:

Writing

Blog writing

Article Writing

Content Writing

Editing

Business writing

Creative writing

Microsoft Office

Letters

Memos

Design documents

Mail merge, mailing services

Reports

Newsletters and management

Excel data entry

Access Databases

Power Point Presentations

Process Diagramming

UML Diagramming

Business Process Consulting and design

Organization charts

Social Media and Email Services

Email Management

Multiple Inboxes

E-mail responses to customer inquiries

Escalate only as needed

Email management, sorting mail, tags

Email marketing campaigns with MailChimp

Website Management

Website Content Management

WordPress

Install Wordpress

Install InfiniteWP for multiple sites

Configurations and setup of themes and plugins

FaceBook, Twitter, Pinterest etc

Technology Coaching

Owner, Designer, Web Master at Sue's Tiny Costumes

September 1995 - Present (21 years 6 months)

- Manage small business including product development, class development, web design & maintenance, marketing & budget
- Write technically detailed, illustrated instructions for processes & doll patterns
- Distance Education Teacher for pattern drafting classes
- Research & write business, marketing, & merchandising plans
- Project management including task management, goals, timelines and GANTT Charts
- Set project goals, determine risks, prepare contingency plan, & time line for achievement
- Collect & analyze data on customers to identify potential markets
- Web site design & maintenance of hand coded websites

- Install & maintain Wordpress sites
- Proficient in white hat SEO techniques
- Track keywords, visitors & other analytical data for each site
- Troubleshoot hosting issues

on hiatus

Office Assistant II at State of Alaska, Division of Senior & Disabilities, Provider Certification & Compliance

May 2008 - February 2014 (5 years 10 months)

Transitioned to the Senior Services Technician as my work as an Office Assistant II became more complex than the Office Assistant II position allows.

- Ability to understand, analyze, apply, & explain complex program statutes, regulations, policies, & procedures
- Communicates effectively with both technical & non-technical users
- Adjust workflow to complete critical tasks in a timely manner
- Develop specific process for processing archival & offsite storage of files
- Policy & procedure development
- Maintain records of files & version controls
- Write technically detailed, illustrated instructions for processes
- Master Certified Office 2003, SharePoint (site owner)
- Visio, Star UML, Project,
- Organizing training sessions; materials gathering, staff/location coordination, equipment setup
- Train additional staff on various processes & assign tasks overseeing accuracy

Career Development Mentor & Computer Instructor at Nine Star Education & Employment Services April 2006 - April 2008 (2 years 1 month)

- Organized training sessions; materials gathering, staff/location coordination, equipment setup
- Developed class curriculum
- Taught computer classes to adults
- Taught goal setting workshops
- Developed basic computer classes or work one on one with students to develop skills
- Answered student questions about various software applications
- Aided students in preparation for the Microsoft Office Specialist exams
- Assessed clients for barriers & brainstorm ways to overcome them
- Drafted & edited resumes, cover letters & other business correspondence
- Conferred with clients to determine what program will be most helpful
- Conducted job-matching to find good fit between clients & hiring companies
- Directed clients to appropriate resources & assists clients in their use of outside assistance

Projects

Professional Curriculum Vitae

January 1994 to Present

Members:Sue Darby

Website which showcases skills in web development, marketing, technical writing, programming languages, software, project planning and management as well as further details about work history.

Application Tracking System with SharePoint

April 2015 to Present

Members:Sue Darby

Created a interim data tracking system using SharePoint to measure the time frames for processing applications. The current in house database does not have this function and the new system is not completed yet. I trained co-workers in use of various views and troubleshoot system as necessary as site admin. System is used for generating reports on where applications and changes are in the processes. This system is being used as inspiration and a guide for building a new report within the new database system going live in

2017.

Habilitation Homes Project

May 2010 to December 2015

Members:Sue Darby

Provider Certification has a number of different providers and even sub-contracted providers of services for those with disabilities. The sub-contractors while important were not found in the internal database and thus no one knew where the clients were being served.

As a brainstorm about this issue I asked management and then IT why we could not connect these contracted homes to the provider oversight agency within the database in a similar fashion to another provider type.

The ongoing project to add contracted providers to the current DS3 database system was born. It is enabling the Provider Certification & Compliance Reviewers to conduct on site visits to ensure health and welfare of clients in habilitation settings thus maintaining compliance with Federal regulations and statutes under the Home & Community Based Waiver Program.

In addition to the initial entry and connections for each contracted home, maintenance for each record is conducted as the host agency is recertified. Additionally, reports have been created to track and more easily see which homes contract with each agency or agencies. This ensures there is less fraud and Medicaid abuse.

Electronic Folder Organization

March 2014 to Present

Members:Sue Darby

Develop a standardized electronic folder system to organize notices, scanned applications and other documentation required for provider certification and compliance. Setup folders, migrate information with IT assistance to new folder system and ensure remainder of unit complies with new standards training and providing assistance and guidance as needed.

Archives

May 2008 to Present

Members:Sue Darby

As the division subject matter expert I have had a hand in the developent of the SharePoint Site that tracks all the files that are sent to Archives or Off Site Storage. Working closely with the techs I helped find and fix bugs in an older system for calculating retention times, update the form to match the required form for Archiving and work as an administrator of the site adding new team members to the site.

Recently there has been a complete change of Administrative staff responsible for part of the process and I was asked to step in to help train them in what the division has done in the last several years. I am also part of a team that is determining the fate of the site as the division moves towards a new database system. Gather, categorize, folder, label and enter into a spreadsheet or database thousands of files dating back to 1996 and prepare for archiving. Oversee volunteer efforts for data entry and correctly calculate the disposition date before submitting for pick up. Recall files for records requests or other litigation as needed. Over 160 cubic feet of data has been sent off site for storage or archiving.

Previously the Archive SharePoint site, built in SharePoint 2007 and converted to 2010 was not computing retention times correctly. I took the lead to work with the SharePoint Developers to update and improve the system. In the process working closely to test and deploy fixes and becoming a site admin for the test and production sites due to my knack for finding the problems or suggesting where the issue might be within the code.

As of October 11, 2016 I just finished the 153rd box of archiving for a total of 5,157 files that I or team mates have entered. I have 6 boxes left that are not in the system... yet.

Self Published Author

June 2001 to Present

Members:Sue Darby

I have had a love of dolls all my life as well as a love of sewing. I combined these loves with a talent for pattern making and wrote not just one book on pattern making for dolls but another for drafting in miniature as well. The two books were a handcrafted and illustrated technical writing achievement that now reside in the Library of Congress as of June of 2001.

Based on the books I took them from print to digital format before it was popular to have electronic books. I also used text based chat rooms to teach classes to individuals all over the world.

Education

Charter College

Bachelors/Associates, Business Management Practice & Office Applications, 2006 - 2009

Activities and Societies: Dean's List, Alpha Beta Kappa, Alpha Gamma Sigma

OSTraining & Udemy

Technolgy, Tech, Personal & Professional Development, 2016

Free Code Camp

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering, 2016 - 2017

Solano Community College

Certificate, Fashion Design, 1995 - 1997

Activities and Societies: n/a

GNC Web Creations Online Search Engine Optimization Class

none, SEO, 2002 - 2020

Activities and Societies: Actively participate in online forum and group discussions on business and building

websites.

Fairfield High

Diploma, 1992 - 1994

Activities and Societies: Scarlet Brigade Marching Band Future Farmers of America

Certifications

Microsoft Office Master

Microsoft March 2009

MSOS: Microsoft Word 2003

Microsoft March 2007

MSOS: Microsoft Excel 2003 Microsoft September 2007 MSOS: Microsoft Access 2003

Microsoft November 2007

MSOS: Microsoft PowerPoint 2003

MSOE: Microsoft Word 2003 Expert

October 2007

Microsoft November 2007

MSOE: Microsoft Excel 2003 Expert

Microsoft March 2009

Try Git

Microsoft

Code School

Try Git

Code School December 2016

Courses

Bachelors/Associates, Business Management

Practice & Office Applications

Charter College

Technical Writing

Project Management

Statistics

Research Methodolgies

Advanced Web Development

Visual Basic.NET

Operations Management Marketing
Office Assistant II
State of Alaska, Division of Senior & Disabilities,
Provider Certification & Compliance
Archiving Basics State of Alaska
Introduction to Share Point with Lab State of Alaska
Introduction to Supervisor Training State of Alaska
Basic Care Coordination Training for QA State of Alaska
Introduction to Office 2007 State of Alaska
Senior Services Technician
State of Alaska, Division of Senior & Disabilities,
Provider Certification & Compliance
COGNOS
HIPAA Security 2008-2014 State of Alaska
Independent Coursework
Introductory JavaScript
PHP
HTML 5
CSS
Basics of Scrum, Agile and Project Delivery

Skills & Expertise Technical Writing

WordPress

MYSQL

Web design

Training

Web Development

Analysis

HTML

CSS

Project Management

Business Analysis

Business Process Design

Process Improvement

Data Analysis

Documentation

Project Planning

Problem Solving

Strategic Planning

Databases

Content Management

Writing

Management

Editing

Research

Time Management

Troubleshooting

Microsoft Office

Social Media Marketing

Quality Assurance

Human Resources

SEO

Marketing

Web Design

SharePoint

Customer Service

Social Media

Event Planning

Marketing Strategy

Event Management

Visio

Organizational Development

Policy

Business Development

Mentoring

Access

Marketing Communications

Team Building

Social Networking

Leadership

Nonprofits Software Documentation Dreamweaver

Publications

Pattern Making for Dolls

Copyright June 1, 2001

Authors: Sue Darby

Step-by-step guide to drafting for small dolls and fashion dolls. Fully illustrated and explained in detail how easy it is to measure and draft patterns "by the numbers" for dolls as small as 8" tall up to 46" tall. Originally self published in hard copy and now available as an e-book.

Pattern Drafting for Miniatures

Copyright June 1, 2001

Authors: Sue Darby

Library of Congress http://lccn.loc.gov/2004540327

Pattern Consultant

International Doll Magazine June 2005

Authors: Sue Darby

Multiple articles in bi-monthly doll magazine including Little Bo Peep, Wedding Gown and "Dirty Dancing" inspired dresses for several dolls

Published Patterns

Dolls In MIniature June 1, 2004

Authors: Sue Darby

Pattern for miniature smocked baby dress for 1/12 scale doll.

Interests

About Sue: http://www.sue-a-darby.com/about.html

Technical Writing, Web Master, Marketing, Business Owner, Photography, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Perl, VisualBasic, Product Design & Development, Document Design, & Formatting, Streamline Administrative Processes, Database Improvements, Data Tracking, Report Processes, Project Management, Task Management, Goals, Budgets, Timelines, GANTT Charts, Master Certified MS Office 2003, MS Office 95-2010, MS Project, MS Visio, MS SharePoint 2007-2010, OneNote, AdobePro X & XI, Adobe DC, Corel Draw Suite, UML. Visio,

Honors and Awards

Alpha Beta Kappa Honors Society, Charter College, Anchorage, AK

May 2009

Life Honors Society for 3.85 GPA

Dean's List, Charter College, Anchorage, AK

Every semester for high GPA

Microsoft Office 2003 Master, Nine Star Education & Employment Services, Anchorage, AK

Microsoft

April 2009

Completed 6 tests for Microsoft office which high passing scores. 2 years of Americorps service as a computer instructor but did not seek Master Instructor despite being eligible for it.

Languages

French

(Elementary proficiency)

Volunteer Experience

Volunteer at AmeriCorps

April 2006 - April 2008

Sue Darby

I look at and analyze your data to help determine where processes could be improved.

sue.a.darby@gmail.com



4 person has recommended Sue

"Sue was one of my students at Charter College. She was on time and completed all of her work in a professional manner. Sue was also helpful to her fellow students."

— Sandra Charlton-Anchorage, taught Sue at Charter College

"Sue was a bright and engaged student, who was always willing to participate and brought great insight to whatever class she was in. I had her as a student in multiple classes, and always enjoyed her presence. Her work was of the highest caliber, and her writing was always clear and well thought out. She worked well in group situations, as well as on her own. Sue would be an acceptional addition to any workplace."

— Dr. Hillary Hodges, taught Sue at Charter College

"I was Sue;s instructor in various courses at Charter College and I have become familiar with her work through discussions with her and in analyzing her written assignments and tests. Her understanding of the course material and her ability to communicate is excellent. I am sure she is going to have an excellent career. In my view, she epitomizes the student who has high aims, intellectual ability, and the drive to succeed."

— William Jamison, taught Sue at Charter College

"I studied with Sue in an online class for SEO. Sue is an inspiration to me and other classmates. Working a website up to number one in the search engines is no small feat and our whole class seemed to click. That was years ago, and we are mostly all still keeping in touch. A bond of sorts was formed with that original class and I am proud to be a part of it."

— Carla Schwille, studied with Sue at GNC Web Creations Online Search Engine Optimization Class

Contact Sue on LinkedIn